My new DMV ID has arrived!

Day 00880: Thursday, 2017 August 03

General news

My new DMV ID has arrived! This time though, they sent me a non-instruction-permit ID card. I wonder if I checked the wrong box on the form. It'd explain why the cost was higher than expected. It'd also explain what the DMV representative thought I was updating. I'm certainly not complaining though. I no longer have to identify as a driver when I'm not one. Being able to identify as a non-driver is almost as nice as being able to identify as non-binary.

Additionally, between both my instruction permits, the expiration dates are the same. Getting the permit updated wouldn't extend the time frame I have in which to learn. I can still use one of the old two permits (preferably the one with my real name (as opposed to my birth name) on it. Honestly ... I'm kind of considering learning to drive. It started with some information I received in the mail from the utility company. Almost all the electricity they provide is from renewable resources. That means if I get an electric car, I can still keep my carbon footprint low. That said, I can't afford a car or insurance right now, so it's not a top priority for me. Eventually though ... if I can get a boyfriend to teach me how to drive, that'd be swell.

Back on the topic of being non-binary, the photograph on my ID came out awesome. I wore my hair down, covering my ears, but not my face. Seriously, it makes me look so much less masculine, and I love it. It's not a viable hairstyle for everyday use yet though, as when I wear my hair that way, it keeps falling in my face. Once my hair is longer, I should have less trouble with it.

I thought more about relationships today, and I think I can and should bend on the vegan home issue. I don't have the strength to go back the the type of home I was in before. My veganism was not respected, but that was only one of the many abusive issues there. If I had a nonvegan partner that was willing to set aside half the kitchen's space for vegan-only items and he didn't simply leave me out of things, I could still thrive. That half could even contain stuff he eats himself; surely he can store half his milk and meat products in half the space or less. Most people don't consume purely milk and meat. As for leaving me out, I mean that if he cooks dinner for us or something, he doesn't give me the same food, minus the bad parts. If he's giving me half a dinner and himself a full dinner, he doesn't truly love me and I need to get out of there. If he eats vegan when with me or provides substitutes for me, I can handle that, I think. Of course, maybe he never cooks dinner, either. If I'm always the one cooking dinner, this won't even be an issue, assuming he's fine with vegan meals he doesn't have to prepare or even come up with. I'm not the type of person to force my beliefs on others; I just need to be respected in my own home.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Mental health watch

I was wrong yesterday. I still feel whole and complete, but I started yearning for sex again. It seems that desire isn't coming from a feeling of incompleteness, but comes from somewhere else in my being. Maybe it comes in waves or something, I don't know. I'm still getting used to this whole being-a-sexual-being thing. For the record, I still don't like it.

While my desire or lack of desire seems to vary, I expect my general mood to remain stable. I'll continue monitoring it over the next while to be sure.

I thought I was leaning more to the feminine side than usual lately, due to the fact that I'm kind of losing my connection to the name Xander. It an okay name, but I don't really feel like it suits me well. I still love the name Lexi though, so that's been making me feel girly. I noticed today though that I've actually liked the name Lex for the past while. That name's masculine, so I guess I still do have both a masculine and feminine nickname I enjoy after all.

I'm questioning things again though. Another thing I thought about was the fact that I've only recently (within the past three years) started wearing shorts. I wasn't comfortable exposing my legs before that. Was that because my legs look too manly? Do I have more bodily dysphoria than I realised? No, it was something else that I'd forgotten about. The sunlight used to make my skin crawl back before I went vegan. I swear, I have some sort of milk allergy, so getting milk out of my system did wonders for me in several ways. It's true too that I want a more-feminine body shape, but I think I don't want to have female sex organs. The idea of sex involving both me and a girl, even if *I'm* the girl, feels wrong to me. Because of the hodgepodge in my brain, the body I want is mixed; like me, my preferred body wouldn't fit the binary options.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Plans for the festival are still on

Day 00881: Friday, 2017 August 04

General news

While sorting laundry today, I noticed a plaid shirt that I failed to remove from my wardrobe before. I actually kind of like that shirt though, so I'm keeping it. How odd though: there exists a plaid shirt that I like. Normally, I hate plaid.

The schedule for the coming week was posted at work today. Thankfully, my day off request was granted. I will be able to attend the festival. Honestly though, if it wasn't granted, I'd've tried to fight for it. I put the request in about a month ago, so there was *plenty* of time for the boss in which to make sure it happened. On my way home from work, a phrase popped into my head; a line for a poem. I can't seem to find rhyming words with the right meanings though to give the poem the sound and flow I want it to have. I've saved the line, along with a couple others and some incomplete lines, for later use. I might find a way to use it in a non-rhyming capacity later, if nothing else.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I can't remember much of my dream last night, but I remember I was working the drive-through window at work. Some customer ordered a "TMI", and I had no idea what that was. They told me it was some pizza listed underneath some other pizza on the menu board, but I don't know what arrangement our menu items are in on the board. A coworker ran out to check, and found the "TMI" was just our standard deep dish peperoni pizza.

Mental health watch

Some part of me still rejects my gayness, but I'm making progress in accepting myself. Have I ever written about when I first learned I was asexual (or that I thought I was, rather)? In late elementary school or early middle school, I forget which, I was taught the basic mechanics of heterosexual sex. I knew right then and there that sex was not for me. I wanted no part of it. We didn't cover homosexual sex though. It was the concept of straight sex that made me reject sex at all. In high school, I used to think to myself that if I had any sexuality at all, I'd partner with a man. I wasn't interested in sex, but I wanted a partner that acted more like the boys acted than like the girls acted. I still thought I was asexual at the time, and when these thoughts would come, they'd just be passing by. However, to my current self, it makes a good case to me that gay is just what I'm programmed to be. I always have been and always will be. I keep thinking that if I can find a boyfriend, and we get to the sexual stage of the relationship, I'll know for sure if I'm gay. I keep thinking that if I can only *try out* that which I've been fantasizing about lately, I can find out if it's really what my body needs. Like if if doesn't go well after several honest tries (and maybe several boyfriends to be sure), maybe I can be bisexual after all. (There are other things I could do with a fellow man, so it's not like if this doesn't go well, I'd be heterosexual or something. These things just aren't what my body seems to crave; they're not what keeps me strictly homosexual.) If my fantasies don't pan out, I keep telling myself I'll find a way to conquer my aversion to vaginas. I already know what I am though. I'm gay. I've always been gay, but not known it until recently. I can't escape it, and I need to figure out how to get myself to stop trying. It's hard though. I guess even despite all the evidence that I'm gay, part of me is still in denial because it doesn't want to be gay. That said, even with my continued internal conflict, I still feel much more stable than I've been in the past while. I feel grounded; I feel like me.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Ripping myself apart

Day 00882: Saturday, 2017 August 05

General news

Soon after waking, I reminded myself that I'm gay. Maybe if I drill it into my head, I'll give up and stop fighting it on any level. It's not like fighting it's going to do any good. I can't make myself not be gay any more than I can make myself like watching sports games or make myself stop having a taste for potato products. It's just not who I am. Potatoes are awesome, sports are boring, and I'd rather die alone than be with a woman.

I don't know what happened, but morgan locked up on me this morning. Hoping it would unfreeze, I left it alone for a bit. The screen went dark, and I assumed the screen saver was starting up. I moved the mouse to wake it back up, but it awoke into GRUB. What? It seems that it rebooted on me for some reason. Once I was logged back in, I found almost my entire bash history had been erased. I'm not sure what's going on, but I hope this was an isolated incident. I hope morgan isn't starting to have serious issues on me.

I took a last-minute bike ride to the credit union today to pick up a rent cheque. It was due today, but I totally forgot until last night. So far, I've never missed my rental due date, but I was kind of cutting it close, this time. I'm lucky it wasn't Saturday; I might not've had a way to get the cheque I needed on time. While I was at the on-site manager's place, I also asked about putting nails in the wall. Is that allowed? It seems it is. I'd never planned to put nails in the wall before, but now ... My mother gave be a gay pride rainbow flag a few days ago. I have all these randomly-placed nails in the wall from before I moved in, but there aren't two that are close enough together to hang the flag well. I've hung it by one corner on one of the existing nails, but it'd be nice to put a second nail nearby and hang it correctly.

It seems my website certificate was never updated after all. I don't know what's going on, but the StartCom Ltd. certificate ended up back in the list of built-in certificates, so my Firefox instance stopped rejecting it. I'm not sure how to proceed. Will my website load in Firefox on other systems now, or has Debian been the only one to take this certificate back into the fold?

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Mental health watch

Perhaps I've been thinking about this gayness issue in the wrong light. I've been waning to be bisexual. However, if I'm bisexual, I'm effectively either gay or straight depending on which person I fall in love with. I don't want multiple partners, so I can't have both worlds. So, the real question is which of the two I'd rather be. Do I want to be gay or do I want to be straight? Not that I have any say in the matter, but I'd rather be gay on most levels. The only reason I'd prefer to be straight is because of the increased ease of finding a partner. On all other levels, I think I *want* to be gay. I'd list off reasons I'd prefer a same-sex partner, but it'd be pointless. I'd rather be bi, so my reasons not to want to be gay have nothing to do with conforming or thinking anything's wrong with same-sex pairs. Without conformation or hating reasons, all that leaves is who I'd want to end up with. I'm gay, so of course I'd prefer a same-sex partner, which means of course I'd rather be gay than straight. I've also always thought same-sex couples (both male and female) are cuter. They just ... look more like they belong together. Maybe that's just because I'm gay though.

I guess, if I'd rather be gay than straight, what that means is that I don't want to end up with a woman at the cost of not ending up with a man. So does that mean I can want to be gay more than I want to be bi? I can't talk myself out of being gay. I tried that, and it didn't work. I'm an animal; I have instincts that I can't override. I could deliberately *act against* those instincts if I chose to, but I couldn't be happy that way and I couldn't actually purge myself of those instincts. However, maybe I can talk myself into wanting to be what I have to be; I'm going to be this, whether I like it or not, so I might as well enjoy it if I can.

I noticed something too. When I try to reject what I am, my personality starts splitting. Self-rejection seems to be very hard on my mind. The most recent case was the Lexi/Xander split, but come to think of it, that wasn't the first. Before that, I had the [REDACTED]/Alex split. At the time, I mistakenly thought the newly-recovered shards of my psyche weren't quite in sync with the part of my mind I was already familiar with. Looking back though, I don't think that's what was going on. My mind was certainly broken and I was certainly recovering pieces of it. However, I don't think any of these newly-found parts could form a personality on their own. Living in an unstable and toxic home environment took a major toll on me, it's true. However, during that period, I never rejected pieces of myself. I sometimes wished that I, entirely, was gone or dead, but it was all-or-nothing. I accepted what I was, I just didn't think that what I was was acceptable. Now though ... I've been trying to accept and reject pieces of myself selectively. I'm pulling my myself in different directions and I'm ripping myself apart. If I want these personality splits to stop (and I do, they're very painful emotionally), I can't selectively accept and reject different facets of my being. I must accept myself or reject myself in whole. And while it's true I have some factory defects, so does everyone else. I'm not a terrible person, as far as people go, anyway. I'm not worth rejecting. I have to accept myself and I have to accept what I am.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The grey skirt

Day 00883: Sunday, 2017 August 06

General news

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I don't remember much of my dream, but one thing stood out. As some point, I found myself wearing a brown, button-up shirt with thin, pink, squiggly lines on it and a thick, grey, knitted, knee-length skirt with thin, pink stripes. The squiggles on the shirt would in some places form hearts. I looked rather cute in that getup, and it wasn't one I'd've thought of wearing. I've considered wearing skirts, but only ankle-length ones. Somehow, I became aware it was a dream, so I forced myself to wake up just so I could remember and take note of that getup.

At some point before that, I'd been wearing some sort of girly shirt, but I changed out of it before going out because I was worried about people judging me. I'm not sure how I ended up in an even girlier getup, but no one seemed to even notice. I didn't even notice until I glanced down while I was sitting and saw the skirt. In the real world, people probably will judge, but I think my subconscious is telling me something. It's no rush or anything, and I don't have time right now, but I should spice up my wardrobe at some point.

Mental health watch

There's nothing wrong with being gay, I just don't think it fits me well. I mean, I had a gay friend in high school, and if I honestly had a problem with gay people, that wouldn't've been the case. However, if gay is the only thing I can be, does that mean I'm wrong? Does that mean that being gay is the *only* thing that fits me? I don't know. It's not like it matters; it's not like I have a choice. I spent the past two months proving that to myself.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Self-acceptance

Day 00886: Wednesday, 2017 August 09

General news

Part of the project I needed to turn in today involved adding a saying. I started to write my own, but it turned into a full free-form poem. Once I have time to work on website structure, I'll probably find a place to put it more permanently. For now, I've put it on the main index page. Finally! The index page has content original to this website, not copied from elsewhere on the Web. As usual, my work is released under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+.

One of my coworkers seems to find my gayness funny. I don't find it funny myself, but at least someone's getting some amusement out of it. I don't care if he laughs, as long as he doesn't avoid me over it. And as long as he doesn't think I'm coming onto him or something. I hear some straight people think gays are coming onto them if they reveal that they're gay. I'm not though. I wouldn't hit on someone without knowing they're gay; I assume people are straight unless told otherwise. Besides, I think he's mentioned having a girlfriend or something at some point.

My bisexual shift leader today mentioned wanting to be of the opposite sex as a child. Just like me. I wonder if wanting to be of the opposite sex is common in the queer community.

My journal is getting kind of long. I think I want to break it into "chapters". Each "chapter" link would just point to the beginning of an arc in my personal story, but they'll serve as bookmarks for finding major events more easily. Today will end the arc of my coming to terms with being gay. I think I've made great strides and can finally stop hurting. It'll take time to get this set up though. It'll likely take some decent code-work to get it set up well. Plus, I'll need to go back and find the exact dates I consider to separate sections of my life. I don't really have time for that right now.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Mental health watch

I noticed today that I'm still being rough on myself. I mean, I'm no longer trying to stop being gay, but I'm still frustrated about it. I need to stop this. I need to learn to embrace this. First of all, that's not fair to me. I can't choose to not be this (I tried), so it doesn't do me any good to keep up the self-loathing. I've been trying to treat myself the way I need to be treated, but I don't need to be scorned for something I can't help. I especially don't need this from myself. I need to go easier on me. Also though ... I expect other gay people to accept and embrace what they are, and I hold myself to a higher standard than I hold others. I expect gay people to own up to what they are and show the world that there's nothing wrong with the gayness. So why is it that I'm not doing that myself? I've owned up to it. Almost everyone I come in contact with regularly knows I'm gay. But why is it that I'm not celebrating what I am? I have to be gay, sure. But I also *get* to be gay! It'll be hard, but this is what I have to work with and I should make it work well for me. Being gay shouldn't be painful like this. I should be setting an example. I have two very-specific needs that only a male can help me with. It's not shameful to seek someone that can help you fill your needs and rule out those that cannot. It's not even like I shun those that can't help me; I just expect them to choose a partner other than myself, a partner they're more compatible with.

(Just to clarify, I don't expect gay people to be open about their gayness if they're in situations that make doing such dangerous. However, I *do* expect it from gay people in safe situations. The more of us that are open about who and what we are, the sooner being gay will no longer be thought to be a big deal. We owe it to ourselves and our kind to come into the light and not hide in the shadows.)

Thinking further, I came to the conclusion that my sexuality should be about making *me* happy. Who cares if my sexuality incorporates some shallow elements? Until I commit myself to someone, my sexuality is mine and mine alone. I don't owe it to anyone. Even if I *had* been bisexual, it I was craving penises, I should choose not to pair with a woman. I should target a relationship that is likely to get me what I want out of live. If I'm stuck with this sexuality, I might as well try to enjoy it. I would be absolutely *appalled* if I heard people were attempting to do what I attempted. I can't think of a single thing I can't do with a man that I could do with a woman either, save for one specific thing. But that thing is obviously not something I can in good conscious do anyway, for several reasons. Besides, a female could easily find a male besides myself; my future male mate might not be so lucky. It's not a bad thing to seek love within a minority group.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The Wonderful Wizard of Oz

Day 00887: Thursday, 2017 August 10

General news

I've been searching second-hand stores for a less-ratty backpack, but I've had no luck. I don't want to show up at the festival looking like I dug my backpack out of the garbage. My last two backpacks have been ones people were giving away because they'd gotten so bad. All but one of the backpacks I've run across in my search have been completely girly. Not just girly, but made for middle school girls or younger. That's fine, but it's not what I want to present as at the festival. The only reason I'd even *consider* using such a bag is because of how masculine my body looks compared to how I feel. Such a bag could help drag my appearance closer to a preferred neutral look. That one bag that wasn't girly was advertising a sports team. I'd rather look like a middle school girl that look like I'm into something as stupid as sports, let alone look like I support a particular team. Today, I gave up the search and bought a brand new bag. This is probably the first brand new bag I've had in over a decade. The masculine bags were either *too* masculine or too expensive, so I went with one that was sort of girly. The repeating pattern includes some pink, but it's a nice pattern and a little pink isn't going to kill me.

I noticed a while back that bicyclists can set off the drive-through sensor at work, but pedestrians can't. I assumed that pedestrians weren't quite heavy enough, but the slight added weight of a bicycle let cyclists cross the weight threshold. A cyclist explained what's actually going on today though. Apparently, it has to do with the metal in the bikes and motor vehicles. It sounds like maybe it's magnet-operated.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

With school almost out for a week, I've checked out from the library the second book on my reading list: The Wonderful Wizard of Oz. In some ways, I think this book will be a better read than the last one, though at the same time, I can't help but think that last book was conductive to my healing process. This time, I used the library's search system that they wanted me to use, so that checks another item off my to-do list once I complete this book.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Pride festival

Day 00889: Saturday, 2017 August 12

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a book you found using Novelist. A librarian can help!
Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody
Read a graphic novel
Get outside: read in a Willamalane park for one hour willamalane.org
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)
Read a young adult or children's book
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country

General news

I tried to take a shortcut to the pride festival. My intent was to find that strange dead-end with the through route that only pedestrians and cyclists can take. Instead, I found that the point in which I turn off of the bike path is not where I'm supposed to turn. The path seems to be a part of Alton Baker Park. Had I been keeping to the path instead of turning away, I'd've had an easy route to Eugene all along.

At the festival, I found there wasn't really a good way to meet people. I could walk up to random strangers and introduce myself, but that'd be awkward. (I should've known a festival wasn't a good way to meet anyone. What was I even thinking?)

All day during the festivities, a drag show was going on. The intro was fun; two of the drag queens exchanged playful banter as they made some announcements and acknowledged the festival's sponsors. The singing after the intro though wasn't my thing. Maybe I would've gotten into it more if they were singing free music, but maybe not; I'm not really into live performances.

I noticed a former classmate, but it was one that tried to avoid me in Winco the other day, so I ignored them today. Clearly, they want nothing to do with me for some reason. I also ran into a former coworker, so we hung out for a while. It turns out they're bisexual. (Why is it that every queer person I know in person is bisexual? What do they have in me that I don't? If being bi is so common, why can't I be bi!?) After a while, I decided to leave them to check out other stands. It was my first time at the festival, and I wanted to see what else was there. After checking out all the stands in a short amount of time though, I quickly grew bored, then lonely. (Why did I leave the only company I had!? That was so stupid and short-sighted.) I didn't see them again, though I did look.

There was a flag vendor with various queerfolk flags, but none were quite what I was after. I guess maybe I should've gone with an agender flag, but my agenderism is more of an internal thing. It doesn't require the approval, validation, support, or recognition of others. At least in my case. While I think being agendered is more central to who I am, I make my gayness more central to my outward identification. If I am to make being gay work, I'm going to need to find a boyfriend, and that requires people knowing I'm gay. The gay flags available weren't to my liking though. Some were the standard rainbow ones. There's nothing wrong with those, but there's no point in my buying one; I've already got one. The lesbian gay flags obviously don't work for me either. I don't have a female body and I'm not seeking a female partner. The gay male flags weren't great though. They were incredibly reminiscent of United States flags. The rainbow stripes took the place of the red and white stripes, and the interlocked male symbols took the plage of the stars. I don't like this country though; I don't want a flag that make it look like I do.

There was a rock-paining stand set up, but I couldn't for the life of me come up with what to paint, so I abstained. After leaving though, I realised I should've gone with stripes in the colours of the agender flag with interlocked male symbols in the middle. Next time maybe, next time.

I saw a gratis HIV test booth set up, but I ignored it at first. I'm a drug-free virgin; I know I don't have HIV, so I don't need to be tested. Walking by again later, I saw they were giving out tee-shirts to people that got tested though. One of the two designs was of a rainbow heart; not a heart shape, but the vital organ. I had to have one. The testing was interesting. First, they asked me several questions about myself. On thing they asked for was my current gender. It was interesting that they'd ask that; I've never had a health professional do that. At the time, I thought it was cool of them to ask. Now that I'm home though, I sort of wonder how my gender was related to anything. After that, they asked for my sex at birth. So ... if I'd had sex-change surgery, that wouldn't've changed anything for their question; they wanted to know what my DNA said I was. They also asked the sex of my sexual partners. At first, I said male, but then clarified that I'm still a virgin, but my sexual partners one day would be male. It turns out that's not good, from an HIV standpoint. Male/male sex is more likely to transmit HIV than any other pairing. I asked why that is, and it's because of anal sex. The inside of the bowels is fragile and weak. It easily tears, resulting in bleeding and an open wound; a perfect opportunity for HIV to spread. (Joy. Just because I'm a gay male, I've got an increased chance of catching HIV. It's not fair. I don't even *want* to be gay. Why can't I be bi!? If I were bi, I'd probably end up with a female partner, just because most people are heterosexual. The probability of finding someone I like that likes me back would be higher for a heterosexual pairing. And why does anal sex have to be the one sexual thing I crave? Again, it just isn't fair. I'm the type to dedicate myself to a single partner. However, if my partner cheats on me, they'll put me at extreme risk.) Of course, the test came back negative as I knew it would, and they gave me a card as evidence. I guess these cards are how you prove to a potential sexual partner that you've been tested recently and that the result was negative. If I reach the sexual stage of a relationship, I guess these cards are how I'll probably get my partner to prove his cleanliness and how I'll prove mine. That said, you've got to have HIV for three months before it'll show up on this test.

It seems while I no longer blame myself for what I am or expect myself to change, I still mourn what I am at times. I guess it can't be helped. I don't own anyone my sexuality, but that doesn't mean that the sexuality I have is one I can be happy with. The world is a terrible place, and the road ahead of me is long and difficult. I keep trying to tell myself it's better this way, but I'm not sure I'm buying it. If I were female, perhaps things would be easier. Then again, maybe they wouldn't. However, as a male, there's basically two options, sexually. There's male/male sex and female/male sex. Which one poses the more unacceptable risk, as a male? I keep trying to tell myself the female/male sex is the worse risk. If something goes wrong, the female could get pregnant. And because I'm the male in that equation, not the female, I can't ensure that there's an abortion. If there's a mistake, an error, I could cause a baby to be brought into the world, and the world's already overpopulated. I can't have that. With male/male sex, the risk isn't on the world, but on me. In a best-case scenario, I find a loving partner and nothing goes wrong. But if something goes wrong, I get HIV. At that point, I have two choices. First, I can abstain from sex forever. I cannot risk passing it on. I've always thought that the key to stopping the spread of HIV is for those that have it to do whatever it takes to stop spreading it. They'd condemn themselves to solitude, but their solitude would do the world a great service; the world could finally be free of this terrible and uncurable disease. It would take all of them doing it though to wipe it out completely. I couldn't do it all, but I could do my part. Second, I could kill myself. I might do that out of devastation. Or I might not. I have a tendency to plan out worst-case scenarios, so I can't help but go somewhere so dark. Why can't I be ace though? Why can't I be free of this terrible risk?

The festival left me feeling kind of bad. It would've been a lot more fun with a boyfriend to hang out with. There wasn't really much point in coming alone. It was important that I come though. I needed to know what the festival was like. If I come again, I should probably rainbow up my wardrobe for the occasion. I'm thinking perhaps I should get one of the more-colourful Floraverse tee-shirts to wear. That said, if I don't have a partner by then, and I probably won't, it might be a better idea to volunteer. I'd meet a lot more people that way, that's for sure, and I'd be a lot less bored and lonely. It gave me hope in a way though. There were so many people there. Many of them probably weren't queerfolk like myself. For example, my former coworker's child was there, as she came with my queer, former coworker. There were probably loads of people there with someone. Even if half the people weren't queer though, there were still a lot of queerfolk. Of course, not everyone that's queer is a gay male, so that cuts down the dating pool further, but there are people around. I think. Admittedly, many of these people might've been from out of town.

When I went to leave, I found my back bike tire was perfectly flat. At first, I thought some hater'd come by and slashed it. I mean, if you hate queerfolk, it'd be easy enough to locate us at the pride festival. Almost any bike you see nearby would probably belong to either someone queer or a queer sympathiser. Instead though, I found the tire had worn through; it wasn't anything malicious. I waited too long to replace the tire, so now that the tire wasn't protecting the inner tube fully, the inner tube'd been damaged. I'd considered replacing the tires because they were bald, but opted against it because I didn't think I needed traction and wanted to save money. So much for that.

I walked to the screening of a gay movie that was advertised at the festival. I'd planned to ride, but my bike was out of commission. I still made it with time to spare, but I had no time to find dinner first. The movie was probably decent, but I'm not really into movies, so it was boring. (Why did I even come to this? I *know* I don't like movies. The movie including gay themes isn't magically going to make it entertaining.)

After the movie, I tried to ask the person serving drinks if they knew where the nearest department store was, so I could get parts for my bike, but they were having a conversation with one of the viewers. After several minutes, I went to the restroom to pass time. I got back, waited several more minutes, and gave up. Instead, I talked to one of the screeners, and asked them. They didn't seem to know, but they did offer me a lift back to Springfield. Honestly, I should've declined, but it'd been a long day and I was weak. The walk home would've taken hours, and I'd chosen to wear shoes today that looked nice, but were very uncomfortable. I accepted the ride, thanked them several times, and did my best to move on.

Once home, I walked to Fred Meyer for the replacement parts I needed. I replaced both tires and the one popped inner tube. The tires cost me a chunk of money I didn't want to spend, but I need my bike. It's my main method of transportation, and without it, my travel distance is rather limited. I don't have the energy to make the repairs tonight though. There'll be time tomorrow. I'm nearly done with my current library book, but the library will be closed tomorrow, so I'll certainly be able to set aside time for bike repairs.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

I knew it was likely I wouldn't find the route I was looking for, so I gave myself plenty of extra time to make it to the festival. I ended up at my destination a little over an hour early, so I found a bench and started reading. I'd brought my borrowed book, just in case. In a surprise twist, Alton Baker Park is a Willamalane park, so reading for an hour there checked off one of my to-do items. I hadn't planned that though; I had no idea who the park belonged to when I brought the book.

I mentioned before the fact that the use of childish language makes the book less fun to read, but it just makes it harder to get into the story. Once you've been reading it a while, it's actually a decent story. Some of the characters are a bit dim though, such as the Guardian of the Gates.

"Which road leads to the Wicked Witch of the West?" asked Dorothy.

"There is no road," answered the Guardian of the Gates. "No one ever wishes to go that way."

"How, then, are we to find her?" inquired the girl.

"That will be easy," replied the man, "for when she knows you are in the Country of the Winkies she will find you, and make you all her slaves."

"Perhaps not," said the Scarecrow, "for we mean to destroy her."

"Oh, that is different," said the Guardian of the Gates. "No one has ever destroyed her before, so I naturally thought she would make slaves of you, as she has the rest. But take care; for she is wicked and fierce, and may not allow you to destroy her. Keep to the West, where the sun sets, and you cannot fail to find her."

That last paragraph is the important one. I included the others only for context. There are a couple obvious problems there though. First, of *course* no one has destroyed her before! That goes without saying. If they had, there'd be no witch. It's not like multiple successful quests to destroy the witch would be possible. Second, of *course* the witch isn't going to let you destroy her! Even if she wasn't evil, most people have a sense of self-preservation.

The section on the witch is surprisingly disappointing if you don't know what you're getting yourself into. She's introduced and destroyed in the span of a single chapter. She's *not* a main antagonist as the cinematic remake would lead you to believe, and in fact, there doesn't seem to be a main antagonist at all. She's perfectly fine for what she was written to be, but if you're looking for an arch-villain, it isn't her. It's also interesting to note that she's got only a single eye, but that it can see further than a normal person could with a telescope. The story isn't clear about if she's missing an eye or if she's got one in the middle of her forehead, but the illustrations (which may or may not have fallen into the public domain like the story has) in the copy I'm borrowing depict her with an eye patch, implying she used to have a second eye.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Working on my library to-do list

Day 00890: Sunday, 2017 August 13

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a book you found using Novelist. A librarian can help!
Read a poem by Oregon Poet Laureate Elizabeth Woody
Read a graphic novel
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read a new book (published in 2016 or 2017)
Read a young adult or children's book
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country

General news

I awoke feeling much better than I had been yesterday, but I was still feeling down about the HIV scare. I cried a few more tears, continuing to mourn what I am. As I changed the tires on my bike (which was a lot harder than it should've been), I couldn't help but play scene after scene of HIV-diagnosis aftermath in my head. I wept the whole time; it was almost like I *had* been handed an HIV-positive diagnosis. I'm still a virgin though. And I'm still drug-free. I'm still clean; safe. As long as my virginity remains intact, I don't have to deal with HIV. As long as I don't rush into anything with a boyfriend and I'm careful enough about boyfriend selection, my risk of a boyfriend giving me HIV should be minimal. I mean, any time another person's involved, there will be some unknown variables. He could cheat on me. If he's good at being sneaky, I might not notice until it's too late.

There are two options ahead of me. First, I can become sexually active (when ready, which isn't now). If I do that, I risk getting HIV. If I get HIV, I'll be obligated to become celibate from then on, to avoid spreading it. I think more than the inability to fight off disease, loneliness will be my curse. My second option is to remain celibate from the start. No HIV, no obligatory solitude. That said, while my solitude won't be obligatory, it'll still be there. A self-imposed solitude will be protecting me from the potential of an obligatory solitude. Will I have really saved myself from anything?

My back wheel seems a bit bent up. My guess is that the tire deflated not during the festival, but before, especially given the size of the hole I found in the inner tube. Riding with flat tires always seems to bend up my wheels. The bike's still ridable though. Some extra wear might happen on the back wheel, but it should be fine. I'd considered trying to bike home on my flat tire, but opted against it, trying to avoid damage. It's a good thing I did, too, as too much more damage might've put that wheel out of commission permanently. I'm not sure where to get a replacement without replacing the whole bike, either.

I went on a short walk to try to put myself back in balance. I guess it helped, and I felt better. On the way home, I felt a small impact on my head, and I figured a large insect had crashed into me mid-flight, but it'd probably continued on. I took my hat off to examine it just in case the insect had stayed with me, and much to my surprise, I found a locust had landed on me. I swear, before moving to this complex, I hardly ever saw any locusts. Several years would go by without my even seeing a single one. This summer though, I've seen three of them, and this last one came to me. I wonder if they like this part of the city better or something.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

I finished reading The Wonderful Wizard of Oz today. It was a good read, though the end was a bit anti-climactic. I forgot to consult my critical books list before choosing it, so it wasn't exactly the wisest book to choose. It looks like my next book should be The Voyages of Doctor Dolittle, a book both in the public domain and that received an award. I can check off the requirement that I read a book that has won an award without reading something proprietary.

The requirement that I read a book published in the last two calendar years still posed a problem though. I was having trouble locating such a book under a CC BY or CC BY-SA license. I thought it was a long shot, but I asked an online community centred around Creative Commons licensing if they had any suggestions. One user was fairly quick to respond, recommending I check out Book Dash or African Storybook. Book Dash was exactly what I needed! The books there are for small children, but they're all under CC BY, and some of them have been published in the past couple years. They've got ISBNs too, so there's no reason the library wouldn't count them. I chose Mogou's Gift (link).

I tried to check out African Storybook as well, but their website is unusable with JavaScript disabled. Had I still been in need of a book, I would've reluctantly enabled it to browse the website, but I already had the book I needed, so I didn't bother.

Mogou's Gift was a very short and very strange story. A gifted child is born with a full set of teeth. One of his many gifts is great skill in painting at about six months of age. However, there's something freaky about his artwork: every painting he paints is of the same place. The child's mother decides they (the villagers) have to find the location being painted. There's no hint of where the place is, and no indication that it even exists. Eventually, the place is found, and it's identical to how Mogou's been painting it all along. They build a city there, altering the landscape so it no longer looks like the paintings, but everyone is happy there, so it's all good. When Mogou grows up, they make him their king. Um. What? For a child, it's probably a pretty good read. For a grown adult such as myself, it's pretty much one big plot hole though. Still, I'm very thankful for this story; it's one less proprietary story that I need to put on my list of books I chose. At this rate, the only proprietary book will be the one meeting the library display requirement. The library chooses what to put on display, so I didn't really have any choice on that one.

Next, I read Girlfriends, a poem my Elizabeth Woody. Proprietary: yes. Book: no. I can't say I really understand what the poem is about or what it means, but that's another item completed.

Mental health watch

I think I'm still a loner. My body has certain cravings, but there's no strong desire for socialising. This may be residual damage to my psyche, but even if so, it might be permanent. If I'm not the social type, it may not be wise to try to partner up, even without the HIV scare. If I'm not the type to hold even a casual relationship, how can I expect to hold an intimate one? I'll continue monitoring this. Until I become more social though, I'm abstaining from romance. It's the only wise move. I won't push it, either. I'm not going to *try* to become more social. I won't try to be what I'm not. I've learned from last time. It'll either happen as the healing continues or it won't. I will try to put myself in social situations and see what comes naturally though. If I don't, there won't be any opportunity to see how I respond.

Job hunt

I filled out most of an application for employment at Fred Meyer, but the website was demanding an emergency contact telephone number. I have ... no one. I'm alone, with no support system. This isn't an unusual requirement, either. I'm going to have the same problem when I apply elsewhere. I'm not sure what to do. Maybe tomorrow, I'll work up the nerve to ask one of my neighbours if they'll be my emergency contact. I'd do it tonight, but by the time I tried to apply, it was already pretty late.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Someone jacked my bike!

Day 00891: Monday, 2017 August 14

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Attend any library program
Read a graphic novel
Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country

General news

When I got out of my self-publishing seminar, I found that someone had jacked my bike! They cut though my lock, and ditched the helmet that I'd locked to the bike. I *just* sunk $55 USD into replacing the tires on that thing! They probably saw the new tires and thought it was a new bike. It's probably not what they expected because that bike has several issues, but it's still wasted money for me on fixing it up and it'll still cost even more to replace the bike.

My neighbour said I might be able to get a bike from Bring for about six dollars, so I'll walk to Eugene tomorrow to try. If I can't get a working bike there, I'll have to walk back, which will be a pain. They said I might have to buy the parts separately and assemble them, which will mean several trips, all on foot. If that doesn't work, I'll need to get one from a second-hand store, which will cost more.

Last time I was there, it looked like they had tones of bikes. I don't know if any were complete bikes, but they looked like it from afar. I don't know how much they cost, but it might be less than elsewhere. It's certainly worth a look.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

I headed to the library to check out the next book. One task was to search a database, so I asked how to search for graphic novels released before the year 1923. The librarian said the database wouldn't be a great way to do that, but a Web search might help. I'd tried that already, but they used different search terms than I did. The results surprised me. That genre of book didn't exist that long ago. There are no public domain graphic novels. I need to read something newer. Out of surprise, I decided to check out whatever, though after walking out of the library with my selection, I remembered that I also have Creative Commons licensing at my disposal. I went back in and checked out The Voyages of Doctor Dolittle as originally planned, though I kept the graphic novel just in case I couldn't find anything online.

I tried again to find free graphic novels online, this time searching for ones under a free license instead of those with expired copyrights. I failed though. I found nothing. I ended up reading the one I checked out, Demon Volume 1. It was interesting, I suppose, but it ends on a cliffhanger. As the series is proprietary, I won't be reading the next volume to see what happens.

I turned in a volunteer application at the local Catholic Community Services office. I'm no Catholic (I'm an atheist), but they're local and might want help. It's not too far from home, either, and I can get the volunteering item checked off my list.

I attended a seminar on self-publishing at the library. For some reason, I was under the impression that it was a seminar on writing, which is why I chose this particular seminar. No matter though. I still learned a few interesting things. First, when you publish, you need to be careful about who owns your ISBN. Whoever owns the ISBN is considered to be the publisher and has full control over your book's distribution. If you go through a channel that provides a gratis ISBN, it's probably not gratis at all. They're not giving you ownership of the ISBN; they're keeping it for themselves, and can veto any distribution of the book that they don't like or that doesn't make them money. Instead, you need to buy your own ISBN. Next, there seems to be something called Preassigned Control Numbers. If you agree to send them a copy of your book when it's complete, they'll give you one of these numbers. While the presenter pushed that you should get one of these numbers, there doesn't seem to be any advantage to doing so. I'd say you might as well, but getting one of those Preassigned Control Numbers requires passing through a CloudFlare CAPTCHA wall, so on principle, I'd say just to ignore the Library of Congress and their numbers. Just don't get a Preassigned Control Number. Next, the EPUB file format is based on XHTML. There's a way to convert from XHTML to $[EPUB], though I'd need to locate the software to do it. EPUB files are important for the same reason XHTML/HTML files are: they allow content to flow according to window/screen size, unlike PDF files. Lastly, MOBI files are in a proprietary format, so it might be good to avoid them.

Mental health watch

I haven't really been feeling very gay over the past few days. Even before the HIV scare, I started wondering if I even want a partner at all. This started a couple days before the festival. I started questioning, wondering if I might not be gay after all. Maybe I was going through some strange emotional stuff. But no. I feel it again today. I'm not having any cravings or anything, but my gayness is still certainly with me. That's good. I've just come to terms with what I am, so having another drastic change in my self-perception is *not* what I need right now. My heart can be whatever, but it needs to make up its mind. I can deal with being gay, but only if I'm going to stay gay for the next while, until I can regain more of my emotional stability. I don't think I have to worry about that too much though; I think I'm going to be gay forever. Sexuality is said to be fluid in some people, but I think my own is pretty unyielding. If my heart couldn't be reshaped when I was trying to reshape it, it's probably not going to reshape on its own.

To be clear though, I'm still a loner, I think. Unless that changes or has changed, it's unlikely I'll decide to find a boyfriend. I might be more social when I have more time in my life though. Once I'm out of school, I might be more interested in going out with friends and/or dating. Now that my sexuality has made its presence known to me and has crammed itself down my throat, forcing me to accept it, it's pretty much leaving me alone.

Job hunt

I was a bit too nervous to ask my neighbour to be my emergency contact, but after my bike got jacked, I did sit down and speak with them. I was going to just put down my own number as my emergency contact, but thanks to a series of tangents, only the last of which was intentional on my part, they offered to be my emergency contact and I didn't even need to ask. They recommended I try to get a bike at bring. I agreed, but mentioned the long walk. They said I could take the bus. I disagreed on the grounds that the bus burns fossil fuels. They asked if I'd ever consider driving a car. I said I would if it were an electric car and I had someone to teach me how to drive. They asked about why my mother didn't teach me. I admitted that I had no idea why my mother didn't teach me before, but that at this point, I wouldn't want her to because she's crazy and I don't want her taking part in my life beyond basic conversation. I said could have my sister teach me if she was here instead of Gresham. Then, as my intentional tangent, I mentioned that I have no one in the area, and that it's causing me issues in job hunting, as they demand an emergency contact. My neighbour, thankfully, volunteered. I guess like my mother, I like when others offer. However, unlike my mother, I wouldn't have blamed my neighbour for not offering if they hadn't. I would've blamed myself for not asking.

I'll work on job-hunting the day after tomorrow, maybe. I'm too frustrated about the stolen bike to do it today, and I'll be on a bike hunt tomorrow.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A slower bike

Day 00892: Tuesday, 2017 August 15

General news

I woke up in the middle of the night, again unable to move my arm. Normally, I use my other arm to shake my paralysed arm in an attempt to get my arm working again faster. This time, I tried an experiment: I didn't do that. I tried letting my arm start working on its own. It seems the shaking doesn't actually speed things up. If anything, it might slow down the process, though that could just be perception. There's no reason for me to shake my paralysed arm; it doesn't help.

I woke up again, way too early. This time, it was too light out for me to get back to sleep. Yesterday, I didn't think the bike-jacking hit me very hard. I was surprised by how calm I was by the whole ordeal. I literally still had a song stuck in my head and was bobbing along to it. I think it actually hit me harder than I'm aware though, and it's making me restless.

Finding a bike that had both wheels and working breaks was a challenge. There were probably about fifty bike frames, and I managed to find two of them that were actually functional bicycles. I chose the one that seemed to be in better shape, but as the tires were flat, I couldn't test it out until after I bought it for $20 USD. The bike is very slow, and it limps. It's hard to peddle, and the positioning of the seat hurts my testicles. I suppose it's probably better than walking, and I'll get used to it, but it doesn't feel that way at the moment.

I forget if I mentioned them the other day, but I ran into someone at a booth at the pride festival, and a service they were offering was help in getting on the Oregon Health plan. I gave them my email address, and they said they'd contact me later to help me. Today, they got in touch, and asked me for several pieces of information. Once I sent that, they said I needed to bring by a pay stub as proof of income. They're in Eugene though, so it would've taken too long to go today; I'd've been late for work. I'll bring it by tomorrow.

At work, a coworker asked another coworker to braid their hair for them. A third coworker jokingly asked if the second was a hairstylist, and said that they know what people say about hairstylists. I wasn't sure, though I had a suspicion, so I asked what people say about them. The third coworker seemed to be trying to walk on eggshells around me though, and didn't want to say. The second, who's the one that seems to find my gayness funny, came right out and said it: male hairstylists are gay. Hoping to get them to relax, I said that maybe I should become a hairstylist then. I continued that line of thought a bit, to show it's really fine. I don't want people on pins and needles around me. It's true that I haven't properly learned to celebrate my gayness just yet, but I've honestly never minded jokes directed at me or jokes about any kind I've ever associated with. I'm not the type to be easily hurt or offended by others, especially when they don't actually mean anything by it.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was on an outing with my mother. I don't remember much, but several key things happened. I remember taking notes on an order pad from my workplace to write about them in my journal later, as I thought I was awake at the time. The last note I took was about how my mother was hating on us transfolk. We'd just come to a group of obvious queerfolk, though the exact nature of their queerness wasn't known to me. One person was male with a beard, but also in a dress. One was female, with rainbow pride hair. I don't remember the others now, the dream has faded in my mind too much. My mother was complaining about how trans people needed to just act according to their sex and saying gender wasn't a separate thing to be considered. I took it rather personally. I felt like if I ever told my mother about my gender (I think she still doesn't know), she wouldn't accept it and would still consider me to be of the masculine gender, even though I'm agendered.

Someone queer asked to see what I what I was writing. Normally, I'm very open with my notes, and I show anyone that asks. When I have a note I don't want misunderstood, I make it cryptic just in case someone does ask. My bisexual shift leader is usually the one to ask, if anyone. With my mother there though, I was was afraid she's want to see too, so I denied the request, as some of the notes were about her and because she's very judgemental. A bit later, I found about five Social Security cards in the back of the order pad. I was confused, but my mother knew what they were there for. Apparently, it was *her* order pad and I was borrowing it. Why did she have an order pad from my workplace!? She started taking the cards out, but I tore my notes out and gave her back the pad.

I used to not consider being agendered to be a form of being trandgendered. However, I'm certainly not cisgendered. That means what I am must be a form of transgendered. One day, maybe, I'll find a subtle way to start the conversation, then explain everything to her.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

My first crush?

Day 00893: Wednesday, 2017 August 16

General news

I took a slightly-different route to Eugene this time. I thought I'd found a spot I needed to refrain from leaving the bike path last time. However, it seems I need to leave the bike path after all, then get on this other bike path that I'd thought was connected. It's not connected, or isn't connected in the way I thought it was at the very least. I ended up getting lost on the way there, but it worked out because I left so early (I was hoping to get home early too).

When I arrived at the street I needed to be on, I travelled down it just enough to get a couple address numbers so I could get my bearings, figure out what side of the street to be on, and find the correct direction to travel down it. Before I could check the address again on my mobile, I noticed the second building I'd looked at for an address actually had the name of the clinic I needed to reach on it. That was easy. It wasn't too far from the main road. The actual process was uneventful. They copied my pay stub, then sent me on my way.

I tried to take an alternate route back, too, so I got lost again. As I take more trips to Eugene though and continue failing to optimise the route, I'll learn the area and eventually get it right. I braked for lunch once I knew where I was, then continued home.

When I got home, too much time had passed. I wouldn't be able to start laundry without fear that it wouldn't be done in time for work. I've already planned to try to visit my mother tomorrow, so the laundry will have to wait until the next day, unless I want to do it tonight or tomorrow, after work, past midnight. (Hint: I don't.)

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed that someone talked me into installing another Linux variant. Supposedly, it was fully-free, and it was definitely quick to install. However, after installing it, I read what the self-proclaimed advantages of this system were over other systems. The list mentioned Debian, saying that Debian was too hung up over licensing. In other words, this system *wasn't* so worried about licensing, and so it wasn't fully free. I regretted installing it, knowing it wouldn't work out, and knew I was going to have to put my laptop out of commission for couple days so I could get Debian installed again.

Library task list

I received an email from Catholic Community Services alerting me to the fact that they think I put the incorrect birth date on the application I filled out. Specifically, the year of the date looked wrong. Sure enough, I accidentally put 2017 as my birth year. Oops. Like a zero-year-old is going to be of any help to them. It's delayed processing of my application, but hopefully not by too much.

Being too short on time to do laundry, I decided to head to the library for what will be the second-to-final book I use for the challenge. At first, I was going to bike over, but decided I'd rather get a short walk in. As I thought about my wanting to walk, I realised that subconsciously, I probably only wanted to walk because my bike got stolen there. I don't want it stolen again, and my subconscious mind is trying to keep that from happening. Seriously; I think my subconscious is fretting about the bike a lot more than my conscious mind realises.

I checked out The Time Machine. If not for the rule that a given book can only mark off up to two squares on the "bingo" board, this would be the final book I need. Instead, once I read this and The Voyages of Doctor Dolittle, I'll take a look at exactly which two squares each book should fill. If I can leave unfilled the most generic squares possible, I might be able to choose any book I want from the library as my final book.

Mental health watch

One of my coworkers accidentally called me by my birth name, which several of them that've known me a while do sometimes. I told everyone they didn't have to switch names an long as the name on my pay cheques was updated, but everyone got on board and started calling me by my preferred name. When they call me by the wrong name, they correct themselves if they notice, and I tell them "Either way." to let them know I don't mind whatever name they want to call me. This time, I overheard him talking to another coworker as I continued dealing with a customer. "It can't be either way though, that's why he (sic) changed it." Yes! This guy understands! I mean, I honestly don't mind if they continue calling me whatever, but I've never liked my birth name, and I want to be rid of it. I thought to myself that I knew there was a reason I liked this guy, and I got kind of a warm feeling. From then on, whenever he was near me, I'd get this pleasant feeling in my butt. I think I got my first crush today.

I can't have this guy though, he's married. To a woman. Not only is he not gay, he's already taken.

It wasn't a strong feeling, nothing even close to overwhelming like I've heard crushes are, and it's on someone I already knew. I've concluded that I'm not the type that fall into infatuation on first sight, though I have had lust at first sight with other people. I think I develop infatuation more slowly, and it'll probably build if I don't find a way to nip this madness in the bud. Furthermore, this dude's a know meat-eater. I guess my heart doesn't care about that after all. That should make finding a mate easier, as I don't have to find a fellow vegan. Furthermore, I've had more-meaningful exchanges with two, if not three, of the women at work. I didn't feel like this, yet I'm closer to those people. I've concluded that I'm not biromantic after all. Otherwise, I would've fallen for these people already. When viewed through the lens of logic, I feel like I could fall in love with a woman as long as sex wasn't involved, but my heart doesn't seem to want to play by the rules of logic. Whatever; I'll figure this out.

Having a heart is stupid. My heart itself is pretty stupid too, if it can't figure out that the married heterosexual isn't a good match for me. Clearly my heart and the rest of my mind are operating on different circuits. Did I mention this guy's cute though, too? I thought he was pretty cute as soon as my sexuality started revealing itself. And I've thought he was funny for years. Come to think of it, he's the same guy that was trying not to offend me yesterday with his gay jokes. He cares about how I feel. I mean, it's not like I'm special to him or anything; he's probably just a caring person. Still, I guess that's what my heart wants: some combination of caring, funny, and/or cute; probably all three.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A stupid customer

Day 00894: Thursday, 2017 August 17

General news

I tried visiting my mother today, but she wasn't at home. I've been trying to contact her for a few weeks, so I thought I'd try in person. Maybe I'll try again tomorrow. Maybe not.

At work, I dealt with the stupidest customer I've yet to deal with. They ordered a pizza, and I told them there'd be a fifteen minute wait, as we don't keep that kind of pizza ready. We rarely sell that kind, so we'd have to throw most of them out if we tried to keep them ready; they'd expire before we sold them. They agreed to wait, then paid for their order. I asked them to come back in fifteen minutes, and that's when they showed their stupidity. They said they'd just wait at the window for it. I showed them that they had customers behind them, and explained that they couldn't block the drive-through lane for fifteen minutes. They claimed that they'd waited in line for half an hour already, and didn't want to have to go to the end of the line and wait another half-hour; they refused to do it. (The head manager claimed they couldn't've been in line for half an hour because the line wasn't that long, but I wouldn't know. More cars joined the line as others left, so it was a continuous stream of customers for quite a while. I wouldn't be able to tell a three-car line from a fifty-car line when the queue was continually added to.) They also refused to get out of their car and come into the lobby, where they'd have no line and their order would be called out as soon as it was ready. I explained that if the customers ahead of them had blocked the line for fifteen minutes each, they'd've had to wait a lot longer than half an hour to get through the line; it'd be a few hours of wait time, at least. I couldn't allow any customer to block the line that long. They still didn't seem to get it, and still insisted that they be allowed to wait at the window and block the line. To get them to move, I told them we wouldn't even get their pizza started until they did. If they wanted to wait at the window, their pizza would never come. Finally, they requested a refund. Now that, I could do. They'd paid by credit card, so I explained that I can't undo the charge, but I can give them cash back. That's how we've been trained to do refunds; whether a customer pays via cash or card, the only way we can issue a refund is by giving them money out of the register. They refused this, and demanded that I undo the charge to the card. What in the world? How stupid are they!? Why does it even *matter* if we refund in cash as long as they get all their money back? I explained repeatedly that we aren't *able* to un-charge a card, but they refused to see reason. Finally, I went and got the head manager and explained all the customer's idiocy to them. The manager went over to deal with the customer; I assumed they'd explain that we can't un-charge a card. Much to my surprise, they instead *did* un-charge the card. So ... we can do that then? As it turns out, only the managers and shift leaders are authorised to do that, so I guess the rest of us aren't even told of the option. Next time a customer refuses cash back and demands that their card be un-charged, I'll just go get the shift leader on duty. I claim it's not a possibility.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

My volunteer application was approved, and I was given a choice or restocking pantries from 09:00 to 12:00 on my choice of either Tuesdays or Thursdays. I think Thursdays will work better with school, should I decide to continue volunteering once school starts. I was instructed to watch an orientation video, where I got the answer to a question I'd been wondering about: does Catholic Community Services expect only Catholics to volunteer with them? No, no they do not. They merely expect volunteers to recognise that Catholic Community Services represents the Catholic Church, so as volunteers there, we'll be the face of the church. If you read between the lines, they're saying we shouldn't act in a way that would embarrass or misrepresent the church. That seems reasonable.

Mental health watch

Having a heart isn't what I thought it'd be, and so far, it's a manageable condition; it's not so bad. I'll admit that the festival was a bust. If I don't find a partner, I'm going to need to learn to keep myself company better at that sort of event. However, it seems I don't necessarily have to look for someone. My heart's going to do whatever, so at least for the moment, my rational mind is of no help to it. My heart and rational mind disagree on who a suitable partner would be. It would be pointless to put in an active search for a partner for the time being. I'm going to end up crushing on men. If I know they're straight and/or in a relationship, I'll leave them alone, and if I'm unsure, I'll try to work up the courage to ask. I'll see where it goes from there.

Is it weird that I feel a little happy about all this? I think part of me *wants* to be capable of these feelings, even though they're clearly being pointed in the wrong direction; at someone who can never reciprocate. Even though my hands are tied and I'm unable to act this time, I'm still enjoying this, at least for now.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

A potential driving teacher

Day 00895: Friday, 2017 August 18

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Read an award-winning book
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!
Read a book that takes place in another country

General news

I was talking with a shift leader at work as we worked, and I mentioned needing to get out of there. I said I needed to get back on the job hunt, and explained how I'd had to halt it for a bit due to the demand that I have an emergency contact, but that now that I had one, I could begin again. They offered to be an emergency contact for me as well! So now, if I need two for some reason, I'm golden. I also mentioned at some point plans to save up for an electric car, but mentioned that I'd need to find someone to teach me how to drive. I wasn't anywhere near the point of looking for a driving teacher yet, but they offered to teach me to drive as well! I might try to take advantage of that offer soon, while it's still available, long before I have my loans paid off and long before I even think about getting a car.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I don't remember much of my dream, but I remember being at work with at least three of my coworkers. It wasn't my real-world workplace, but I remember three of my real-world coworkers being there. There was the one that thinks my gayness is funny, the one that got weird at first when he found out I'm gay until I told him he's not my type to calm him down, and the one that loves horses. The place had certain characteristics of my real-world workplace, but was an entirely different place. This place looked a lot like a warehouse on the inside, but without as many shelves. It was large, and had a huge, walk-in refrigerator.

A stupid customer had pulled up to the window, skipping the menu board. Unfortunately, I was right in front of the window when it happened, so I couldn't simply avoid the window. I pretended not to see them, and continued working. Apparently, the window was open. After waiting a bit, they pulled a bit more forward, so instead of the driver still being aligned with the window, the back passengers were. One of the back passengers spoke, and they were too loud for me to pretend not to hear, seeing as the window was open. I instead pretended to be startled, then explained that we have no sensors at the window, and that customers are supposed to order at the menu board. They said they knew that, but didn't care; they didn't want to order at the menu board, so they just decided to skip it. I started taking their order at the window, but before we got anywhere, they seemed to already have their food in the car. I thought they'd reached through the window and stolen it when I wasn't looking, but soon, I saw the my two coworkers that aren't the horse lover had joined them in the car. Those two must've been chummy with the rude group and brought them gratis food.

I'd brought into work a bucket full of candies to share with my coworkers at some point. While I wasn't looking, a rude and unappreciative coworker dumped a bunch of them on the table and on the floor. I got the feeling it was one of the two that were chummy with the rude customers. In the real world though, I don't think either would do that.

Library task list

I finished reading The Voyages of Doctor Dolittle. It was an okay read. Again though, it'd be nice if I could've filled my reading list with less children's books and more adults' books, but trying to squirm my way out of reading copyrighted material limited my options for filling reading requirements. I needed a book that took place in a foreign country and one that had won an award; this book met both requirements.

I started reading The Time Machine, and very quickly, it jumped to something thought-provoking. Some people claim that time is a fourth dimension, akin to the three spacial dimensions. However, the on the first two pages of this story, the book made the only convincing argument I've ever heard for that. Starting with one- and two-dimensional objects, these objects cannot exist because they lack other dimensions. For example, an actual, geometric line has length, but had zero width and zero depth, so it's only an abstraction. It can't exist in the real world. A plane has no depth, so again, it can't exist. On the surface, a three-dimensional object seems to exist, but it can't actually exist for a nil amount of time. The object occupies a fourth dimension, time, a dimension measured as the object's *duration*. ... or so the book argues.

Mental health watch

Based on my feelings over the past few days, I think I can learn to love being gay. It will most certainly be an *acquired* taste for me though. As being gay involves having a heart (as would being *anything* besides aromantic asexual), I'm going to need to put in some work. First, I need to extinguish my need for a partner. I don't need to extinguish the *desire*, but it can't be a burning, aching need. I may have already achieved this, so perhaps mission accomplished. Second, I can let my heart lead me to a lot of places, but there are boundaries I can't let it lead me across. Such as hitting on known straight people. Like seriously: why do I have a crush on a married heterosexual?

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I need to fix my issues

Day 00896: Saturday, 2017 August 19

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Read a science fiction title
Share a book recommendation
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!

General news

I dealt with one incredibly stupid customer today. Some customers like to drag their order out into five or six pieces instead of giving me their full order all at once. This makes it incredibly difficult for me to remember it all. If they only gave it to me all at once, I could remember many more items. This customer pulled that stunt, then when I forgot one of the items, and thus didn't charge them for it, they tried to get me to give it to them gratis. I explained that I hadn't charged them for it, and they said they shouldn't have to pay for my mistake. Um. If I didn't make the mistake, you'd've already paid for that item. Your total, in the end, is coming out just the same. No, you don't get gratis menu items just because you gave me your order in segments and *you* caused me to forget part of it. You don't get *rewarded* for being a pain to work with. You'll pay the *same price* everyone else would pay. Moron. Of course, I explained it in a much gentler way and left out the part about how it was their own actions that caused me to forget to charge them for an item, but the gist of of what I told them's the same.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was running the drive-through at work again. The coworker that thinks my gayness is funny pulled past the menu board with a couple other people in their vehicle, and came straight to the window. (Why do I keep dreaming about this person lately?) As per protocol, I ignored them, and started working with the customer behind them that actually stopped at the menu board like they were supposed to. This person was in a panic. I couldn't make out what they were saying through the headset, but from the way they sounded, I thought someone was pursuing them and they needed help. I asked them to come to the window so I could better hear them, then as the window was blocked by my coworker and their gang, I headed out a door on that same wall to meet the customer. (We don't have such a door in the real world.) As it turned out, the customer was in no actual danger. They were having trouble with our ticket machine (which again, we don't have in the real world). They'd inserted their money, but their ticket never came out. The outside of the machine was wooden for whatever reason, though the inner components that stuck out a bit were metal. I gently pulled at the line of tickets, and got one out for the customer. They were happy, and drove off. I'm not sure what the tickets were for, but I somehow got the impression that they might be for our car wash (which again, we don't have).

I continued trying to work tickets out of the machine to figure out why the tickets weren't simply coming out as the customers paid for them. As I did, I found other things jammed up in the machine's ticket roll, which probably caused the problem. I forget what all I found, but there was larger amounts of cash rolled up with the tickets. In one case, I found a hundred-dollar bill. There were also miniature condoms, still in their wrappers. The condoms were the more-likely culprit as the cause of the jam due to their thickness. Somehow, I was able to open up the machine, though I don't remember doing so. Inside, I couldn't access anything of importance, as all the components were in another chamber of the device. I'm not even sure why the chamber I opened even existed. In that chamber though, jammed into a corner (which wouldn't've affected ticket dispensing) were several coins. There were at least five quarters, as well as some other coins.

Somehow during that, the dream story got modified, so I was no longer at work. I'd instead allowed myself to get separated from a group at some activity fair, and the people running the fair weren't happy about it. I'm not sure how, but I overheard them discussing my separation with one another. I was no longer trying to unjam the machine, but trying to get as much money from it as I could. I pocketed everything I'd recovered from the machine, and locked the machine up with one of the keys on the lanyard that's usually around my neck when I'm away from home. I then tried to rejoin the group without making too much of a scene, though I was directed by signs and people to go elsewhere. I woke up before I saw where they were leading me.

Library task list

I finished reading The Time Machine. It was a pretty good read, though I still like that first chapter best because of the explanation it was written to convey.

My intent was to finish the book today, then figure out what the next book to read was and read it tomorrow. I forgot that tomorrow is Sunday though. Again. I won't be able to check out the next book until the next day. I'll get my book information sorted tomorrow and get my final book picked out, but the reading of it will have to wait. I'm nearly done with the challenge though!

Mental health watch

I read some depressing information today. Lesbians are known to be quick to commit to a relationship. However, gay males are known not to commit at all. They're known to sleep around and not really do any serious dating or hold actual relationships. This, of course, is stereotypical gay males, and doesn't hold true for all of us. I, for example, don't want sex until I'm sure I'm into my partner and I'm sure he's into me. I seek monogamy. However, this stereotype is no doubt because of a common trend in gay males. That's going to make finding a suitable life partner even more difficult.

Knowing this greatly frustrated and upset me. I spent a fair amount of the day loathing my gayness and how difficult it's going to make life. Clearly, I haven't stamped out my need for a partner fully. I need to spend more effort fixing this. If I don't find a partner, I *need* to be perfectly happy on my own. I *need* to not allow it to hit me this hard.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Male-pattern gayness gene?

Day 00897: Sunday, 2017 August 20

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Share a book recommendation
Suggest a library program you would attend
Read something funny and have a good laugh :)
Look at the art in the City Hall Gallery. There's a new show every month!
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!

General news

I tried to visit my mother again, but she wasn't there. Maybe she's out of town or something ...

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

I started working of figuring out which book to use for each of the "bingo" squares, and found what I thought to be a limiting factor. I hadn't read a funny book yet. I decided I'd need to find a public domain joke book to pass off that requirement, but after a while, I remembered that I laughed at a funny section in The Wonderful Wizard of Oz: the part in which the gatekeeper said no one has ever slain the Witch of the West before. That book was the one I read in the park, and also the one I looked up using the library's Novelist database. Each book can only count for filling up to two requirements, but both those requirements are pretty generic. If I make the final book I check out fill one of those two, I can use The Wonderful Wizard of Oz as my "read something funny" book, and my final book can be literally any book I want it to be. Finding a single, enjoyable, public domain book in the entire library shouldn't be much of a challenge at all. I'll figure out what book I want, look it up in Novelist, then check it out and read it. I still need to make something though based on a book. With how thin I stretched these books for requirement-filling, the thing I make will need to either be based on The Time Machine or the final book I check out. None of the other books will work, either because of copyright issues (in the case of two books) or because those books are needed for other "bingo" squares.

I *could* say I made part of a journal entry already on each of the books I've read for the challenge, but that doesn't seem like it'd be in the spirit of the game. I considered doing what the librarian suggested, and checking out a cookbook. They said if you make something from one of the recipes, that would count. I'd like to archive what I make though, just to hold onto it longer. I could draw something, but I don't have a scanner set up. Maybe I'll try digital drawing, and make a collage of things from each of the books I read for the challenge, with the exception of the two proprietary items. It'd probably be technically illegal to include those in the collage anyway.

Mental health watch

I'm starting to wonder if I'm really the mutant freak I think I am. Homosexuality seems to be incredibly common in many species of animals, and extremely prevalent in some of them. It seems that every species of great ape, humans included, have some homosexual members. In some species of animal, homosexuality is even more common than heterosexuality. One study of giraffes observed 94% of sexual mounting to occur between two males. What is going on here? And the giraffes still continue to repopulate and continue existing. In one species of sheep, at least 8% of rams seem to be attracted exclusively to members of their own sex. Is homosexuality actually *advantageous* in animals, including humans? I mean, obviously having *only* homosexual behaviour would kill off a species, but perhaps homosexuals contribute to the survival of genes passed by their parents. Perhaps the possibility of spawning homosexual descendent is somehow selected *for* more than homosexuality itself is selected *against*. If the role of my kind isn't direct reproduction, what *am* I to the survival my species? How does my desire for a same-sex pairing contribute to humanity as a whole?

I continued my research, and it turn a sharp, grim turn. It's still not completely known, but it looks like in humans, there's likely a gene on the X chromosome that's often responsible for gayness in males. This gene, when in females, makes them more likely to produce a large number of offspring. In males though, it makes them gay. Women that don't have this gene are therefore like factories that produce a slow stream of high-quality goods. Their children grow up and pass act as factories themselves, passing on the DNA of their parents. Women who have this gene though are like faster, less reliable factories. They usually have a fifty percent chance of passing this gene on, as it's only present in one of their two X chromosomes. (For it to be present in *both*, they'd need a gay father to give them one of their X chromosomes while also needing a gene-carrying mother to pass on the gene via the other X chromosome, which is unlikely in practice.) The father has a fifty percent chance of passing on either sex chromosome, resulting in four options total: male carrier of the gene, male non-carrier, female carrier, and female non-carrier. The male carriers are gay and don't pass on their genes, essentially making them defective goods. If the faster factory is able to produce more functional goods than the slower factory, it doesn't matter how many defective products are produced. It's only the functional ones that even matter. But that makes me ... The waste product. The defective good. The reject. I have no role; my creation was just bad luck, and the wrong egg met the wrong sperm, so I'm that one-in-four factory defect.

Now I feel hurt, and a bit resentful of nature. It's not fair; none of us should have to be defective. That said though, life never has been fair. This really is the least of our problems.

My mother had four children, which is a lot. She wanted seven though. I think it's pretty clear that she's very likely to have this have-lots-of-children-if-you're-a-female-but-be-gay-if-you're-a-male gene. My mother's also completely uninterested in pairing with a woman. Several lesbians have come onto my mother, and she gets frustrated and tries to get them to knock it off if the same lesbian tries repeatedly. It's completely understandable, but it shows a complete disinterest in women sexually. Which is about what I feel, though I don't have people of either sex frequently come onto me. I did one time have a woman try repeatedly, back when I thought I was asexual, and it was an incredibly uncomfortable experience. For the time being, I'm convinced I inherited my mother's sexuality, or at least the component of it that results in being exclusively attracted to males. My mother's mother had four children as well. Again, this points to the potential to carry this gene, and the potential to pass it to my mother. That's where I hit a dead end. I don't know my family tree any deeper than that. My grandmother's two male children have children, but those children aren't interesting for this theory, because those two males are heterosexual. They wouldn't have the male-pattern gayness gene. Do gay males run in our family tree further back though? I can't help but remember that that one book I read for the library challenge also hinted at a male-pattern gayness gene passed through female family lines.

Assuming this theory is true, my biological purpose was complete the day I was conceived. The male-pattern gayness gene lives on my multiplying enough that it doesn't matter that an estimated half of its heirs won't pass it on. That leaves me without continued purpose, but maybe I can turn that into a good thing. I'm free to do whatever makes me happy, as I have no further obligation to biology and evolution.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Finally met with my mother

Day 00899: Tuesday, 2017 August 22

General news

I stopped by Bi-Mart to check the lucky number drawing for the week, then continued to the credit union to deposit my pay cheque. I'd planned to deposit it yesterday, but decided to postpone it a day so I could hit Bi-Mart on the same trip. I took a route home that led past my mother's house, not thinking she'd be there, but wanted to see just in case. She actually was home this time, so I dropped in. She's still blaming my "telephone" for the communication issues. I keep trying to explain that there's no telephone on my end and that I'm using email, but she doesn't seem to get it. I explained to her though that my messages are getting through to her carrier, and explained how I'd know if they weren't because my email provider would let me know about messages that failed to deliver. I explained it's her carrier failing to get the messages to her. I'm not sure this made any impact on her understanding of the situation though. Vivian was there as well, so I got to see my sister for the fist time in a while.

When I got home, one of my neighbours alerted me to the fact that another neighbour is giving away a bed. Sweet! I went and talked to them about it, and they're giving it away once their new bed arrives, which will be within the next couple weeks. From the sound of it, there's a mattress and a frame, but no headboard or footboard. Perfect! I don't need a headboard/footboard, but it'd be nice to get my bed up off the ground. As an added bonus, the mattress is still in plastic, so it's probably in great condition (at least on the outside) and clean. I can't be sure the frame is included though. They said the bed had "the metal part", which I assume to be the frame, but as they were giving it away, I felt it'd be rude to try to get them to elaborate.

Discover is still pestering me about giving them Yst Dawson's Social Security number. I think I outright ignored their last two requests, not even noting them in my journal. This time, I took the opportunity to ask them for a new card. They have this option where you can request as many cards with different designs as you want, and they'll all have the same card holder name printed on them and will all be linked to the same account. I think as they continue pestering me, I'll keep asking for new card designs, if I think I'd actually use those designs. This time, I chose their rainbow design, which they named "Pride". To be honest, this might be the only extra design I request, besides the basic, light blue one they start you with. I might also get their pink, monogrammed one, but maybe not. I'd be less on the fence about it if it came in other colours besides pink. Pink's okay, but it's not really my colour.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Oz might be a place for queers.

Day 00901: Thursday, 2017 August 24

To-do list

Acquire stuff for my new home:

A bed
A dustpan
A carpet broom

Inform people that I've moved

Relevant online accounts

Finish stabilizing include.d and put out another release (low priority)
Clean up my apartment

Clean up the kitchen

Finish the library's "bingo" sheet (these tasks were typed verbatim, and include any mistakes and quirks present on the sheet handed to me)

Browse the Gale Virtual Reference Library. A librarian can help!
Build, draw, or make something based on a book that you read
Share a book recommendation
Volunteer for a couple hours at a community organization of your choice.
Download one of the library's free apps or search in a database. A librarian can help!

General news

The other day, someone pointed me toward the term friend of Dorothy, a slang term referring to a gay male. The Wikipedia article on the term mentioned that the original, unextended series featured several queer-friendly plots. I'm starting to notice this now. I question the "crush" Dorothy supposedly had on the china girl in the first book. Dorothy wanted to use the china girl as a shelf ornament; that doesn't seem romantic or sexual in any way. In the second book though, you read about a princess that got turned into a boy as a baby, in order to hide her away. Once her location is discovered, the witch of the south wants to return her to her original form. However, she doesn't want to be a girl; she wants to remain a boy. Either this cisgirl was transformed into a cisboy, meaning that her personality was altered in the process, or he never was a she at all. He was a transboy that got transformed into a cisboy. I've finished the reading portion of the library challenge, so I'm not likely to spend my off-work hours reading library books. I'm reading them at work on my breaks still though. I've started the third book in the series, and you quickly meet a hen that was mis-sexed as a chick. She got named "Bill", then when she grew into a hen, her owners never renamed her. It seems parallel to how transfolks get misgendered at birth. It's not quite the same, but I can see why this would be considered a queer-friendly plot point. That said, unlike misgendered humans such as myself that were poorly named, this mis-sexed hen doesn't care about the gender of her name. Dorothy makes a point of feminising her name into "Billina", but the hen doesn't care about this one way or another, stating that any name is fine so long as she knows it refers to herself.

The franchise owner has been coming into our workplace lately and throwing stuff out. Earlier, they threw out all our aprons, then ordered new ones. They didn't order new ones, wait for them to arrive, then throw out the old ones; they threw the old ones away first, leaving us with no aprons. So we've been dealing with that lately. Now, I found they've thrown out our trash cans. This time, they waited for the new ones to arrive first, but it's still a waste of good trash cans. I managed to find and salvage the trash can with the most damage to it, but I couldn't see the others; they were likely buried in the dumpster, and I wasn't going to go digging. Once I get this thing washed out though, I'll have a nice, large trash can for my entry area, and I won't have to take the garbage out quite as often. Or maybe, I'll use it as a place to store returnable bottles before I take them in for deposit.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Library task list

I was scheduled to volunteer for three hours, but they only needed me to work a little over two. I got out early, but at least it wasn't *too* early; I needed to put in at least two hours for that library challenge. It's tiring work though; I was famished by the time I left. I should've brought a snack of some sort or had a bigger breakfast. Some of the work hurt my back, too; I might want to wear my back brace next time and see if that prevents it.

I finished reading The Marvellous Land of Oz. That completes my reading for the challenge. I don't have much left to do before I turn in my sheet. I also searched the virtual reference library, which as I should have guess, is a reference library. I thought it'd have most of the same books the main library had for some reason, but nope, it's just reference books. Furthermore, there aren't any old, out-of-copyright books there. I located a book, Online Schools, to check off that requirement. Thankfully, I didn't have to actually read the book, only find it, so that didn't add another proprietary book to my reading list.

Mental health watch

I was thinking about my strangeness in needing a commitment before sex even though I'm a gay male and gay males don't tend to want a commitment. I wonder if it has something to do with the fact that I'm agendered. I'm a gay male, but I'm not a gay *man*. I'm not a real boy, so I don't *think* like a real boy. I have different needs, different desires.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Compromises in code

Day 00902: Friday, 2017 August 25

General news

As I was heading out the door to go to work, I was rummaging through some stuff and found a certificate from the HIV Alliance. It offers a gift card to people identifying as men that have sex with men if they take a gratis HIV test at their Eugene office. I was thinking it'd be easy money. It wouldn't be worth the time and energy to bike out there for it, but it'd be a nice excuse for some exercise as long as I admit the money's not the main reason for going. But then I realised that I don't qualify. I don't identify as a man, but even changing that to males that have sex with males ... I'm a virgin. I'm hella gay, but I don't have sex with *anyone* yet. It strikes me as peculiar that I'm a gay male, but I'm not a male that has sex with males. It makes perfect sense, but it still feels almost paradoxical.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

include.d

I hit a bit of an issue while trying to set up the type-hinting for my code. When functions and methods are not supposed to return a value, this can't be enforced. I'm going to need to rewrite my functions and methods to always return a value of some sort. If there's no possible helpful value to return, I guess I'll return a constant boolean or something. A bit after finding this limitation, I found that it was actually fixed in a later version of PHP. That'll definitely help with future code, but it won't help now. I develop for the version of PHP that ships with Debian Stable for greatest compatibility. I can't make use of this fix just yet, and by the time I can, my rewrite should be long past complete.

A few methods in one of my wrapper classes can't be fully updated to make use of the type hinting, and won't be able to even with the later update. One takes a value as a parameter that can be either a string or an integer. Another returns a value that can be a string, an integer, or a boolean. I could break these methods into multiple methods, but I'm reluctant to do that. The class is just supposed to act as a thin wrapper, binding a resource handle to the functions that operate on it. A third method requires an object as an argument, but that object may be of any class. I can't type hint for general objects. Similar issues were present in my other wrapper class as well. I think I'll just leave the new feature use out here. I fully intend to update all my non-wrapper classes to conform to the strict type-hinting though.

That is, at least when not implementing built-in interfaces or providing callbacks for built-in functions. It seems that when implementing an interface that doesn't make use of type-hinting, parameters can't be type-hinted. I don't have a way around that. Also, some callback functions need to accept a resource handle as an argument. That can't be type-hinted for either.

I've finished up pretty much all the update, with the exception of the URI-handling code. That code's a bit complex, and, as I said before, the documentation on it's out of date. I thought I'd finished up the code of the main abstract class, but then I got to the main class that descends from it. The main issue there is that the return value types have been changed in several key methods. I'll need to finish updating this class, then go back and fix up the abstract class to allow the child class to even descend from it. Then there's the fact that I can't enforce null return values, so I need to alter the code to provide reasonable return values where possible. Several methods operated on arrays without copying them, but to provide decent return values, that'll need to change. Passes by reference will need to be removed, and code that called those methods restructured. It'll take some time, that's for sure. And once it's all complete, I'll need to go through the documentation and finish updating it.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Rainbow card

Day 00903: Saturday, 2017 August 26

General news

My new, rainbow-design Discover card arrived in the mail. It's a lot more reflective and shiny that I imagined it'd be, and it's got a purple back on it. I can't imagine me using another Discover card for quite a while, so I think I've had my fun. I probably won't order another card next time Discover pesters me about Yst Dawson's Social Security number. Speaking of demands for personal information, they recently made a demand for more of mine. Now they wanted to know my country of citizenship and my employment status. As a show of good faith, I gave them both, as I've been withholding Yst Dawson's Social Security number (as it doesn't exist) and I don't want them thinking I'm just being obstinate. That said, Discover should already know my country of citizenship. I find it highly improbable that they wouldn't know that already.

The cute guy at work got a haircut. He's much less cute now. Previously, he practically had a *mane*; He had a thick beard, a nice moustache, and decently-long hair. Now that's all trimmed up, and I dare say he looks "normal". I suppose he looks nice enough, but it's a downgrade from his previous style.

We had a mad customer rush most of the day today, and in my hurried state, I made a mistake on an order. I told the customer I'd fix the order for them, but they still wanted to keep yelling at me. I explains that because of the frantic rush we were in, mistakes were bound to happen, but they didn't care. They somehow thought I could fill every order perfectly while under the increased pressure and with greater speed. Some people just think nothing about others, but only themselves.

A long time ago, before I had this journal, we used to have a cyan-skinned customer come in fairly regularly. I assume they have cyanosis or something; a symptom of a bigger health problem. Slowly, I saw their skin become greyer, and I was always concerned for them when they'd stop by. They were always in such a cheerful mood when they ordered though. At some point, I left the company, so I didn't see them again. When I came back, they never seemed to come by any more. Honestly, after not seeing them for a while after coming back, I assumed they'd died. Clearly, they weren't in the best of health, so it seemed likely they couldn't keep going any longer. I left the company again to go to Coos Bay, and when I returned yet again, I no longer really thought about this former customer any more. Today though, they came back. They're as grey-skinned as ever, if not greyer. They're not as cheerful as I remember them being, but it's been a while, so I might remember wrong. They still seem pretty cheerful and happy though.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Spliced application forms

Day 00904: Sunday, 2017 August 27

General news

Vivian came for a visit, and we talked for about five hours, catching up.

She brought over some mail meant for me that somehow made its way to our mother's house. Oddly enough, it was addressed to Alex Yst, but was sent to the wrong address. I didn't have that name before I came to live here, so that didn't make any sense. From the envelope, I could tell it came from the Oregon DMV, so I didn't bother with it right away. When I did open it, I was surprised to find all three letters weren't from the DMV after all, but the Oregon Health Plan. What in Squiddy's name? When I applied for health coverage at that address, they kept erasing the forms I filled out. I applied only under my old name, as well. At my new address, with help, I applied for coverage under my current name and address. I double-checked the form I sent the clinic representative too; I gave them my current address, not my mother's address. My best guess is that something is seriously broken in their system (besides the break that kept erasing my filled form and the break that made the website keep telling me there was a message to log in and see when there wasn't one) and that my forms got spliced. They probably got matched by Social Security number or something, while the name from one and address from another was used. I swear, their system is incredibly buggy and moronic. I've written back to the clinic representative to see if they can help get this sorted out.

I came to an interesting conclusion today while thinking about random things. Previously, I figured I'd find love it I happened to stumble upon it, and I wouldn't if I didn't. It'd be as simple as that, especially once my mind is more stable. When I was desperate and highly unstable, I considered online dating, but I gave up on that idea as my stability began returning to me. As my mental stability increases, my need for a partner decreases, so I thought there wasn't a need to actively search for a relationship. However, today, I realised how wrong I was in that assessment. If I find love through a chance meeting, such as if I happen to get to know someone by working alongside them for a while, we're not likely to share the same values. There's going to be a clash, and I'm going to have to bend quite a bit. I was prepared for that. However, with online dating ... I can look through the profiles of several people in a relatively short period of time. I can look for people that would make a better partner for me on a mental level; and I'll be a better partner for them as well. A perfect match still isn't going to happen, but the chances of lifestyle clashes might be a lot lower. For example, who, like me, wants to live in a television-free home? Not many people seem to want that, but I can add keep that on the list of qualities I search for in a man.

My canary still sings the tune of freedom and transparency.

Document modifications

On 2018-01-16, my sister, Vivian, requested that I replace all instances of her legal name in my journal with the name "Vivian". She also asked that the name of the organisation she works for be redacted. This page was modified to fulfil that request.

Copyright © 2017 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.